# Lewi Gilamichael

(240) 423-3573 | Brooklyn, NY lewi.me | github.com/lewi-g | lewi.dev@gmail.com

## FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Experienced with building greenfield projects using Node, React, Redux and TDD.

Skilled at writing clean, testable, efficient code using current best practices.

Dedicated to learning and remaining up to date with recent coding frameworks and advances like GraphQL.

## **KEY SKILLS**

Front End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML, CSS

Back End: Node.js, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Passport, bCrypt, Heroku, RESTful API, GraphQL

Workflow & Testing: Git, GitHub, Webpack, Travis CI, Cypress, Mocha, Chai, Enzyme, Jest

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Freelance: Web Developer 10/2018 - Present

- Develop e2e tests with Cypress for a complex internal web app
- Coordinate with team through Slack and JIRA

The Coding Space: Curriculum and Web Developer 12/2017 - Present

- ° Use the Socratic method to guide students through troubleshooting and developing their projects.
- ° Design and implement curriculum materials for consumption by our students.
- ° Teach the use of working environments: Scratch, Woofjs.com, and JS Bin.
- Spring and Summer Camp Director

**Projects:** 6/2017 - 10/2017

**Prioritize**: prioritize-app.herokuapp.com

- Productivity app designed to make your life easier.
- Built with Node, Express, Mongo, React, Redux

**EpiQuotes**: epiquotes.herokuapp.com

- A quotes database populated by users.
- ° Built with Node, Express, Mongo

**Dig Deep**: emotion-mapper.herokuapp.com

- Diary for tracking changes in mood and the associated event to help users identify trends.
- Built with Mongo, Express, React, Node

**Johns Hopkins:** Clinical Laboratory Scientist, 2009 - 2016

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Thinkful

# Full Time Web Development Intensive, Jun-Oct 2017

- Daily lectures, exercises, pair programming, and group projects with the #1-rated webdev bootcamp.
- ° Learned HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, algorithms and data structures.
- Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards by collaborating several hours each week with a senior web developer.

University of Maryland, School of Medicine

**B.S. Degree in Medical and Research Technology**, May 2009